Nicolás Marguglio

✓ nicolas.marguglio@gmail.com — • azimut

January 19, 2023

about me

I spend most of my professional carrer maintaining and designing high-scalable Linux systems. More recently, I have been learning how are those systems build from the programming side.

admin skills

Tools emacs, git, tcpdump, nmap, docker, ansible

Servers Apache, Nginx, Kubernetes, qemu, dnsmasq, qmail, postfix, dovecot

DB mysql, postgres, elasticsearch, redis, OpenLDAP

OS Gentoo, Red Hat

programming languages

Advanced common lisp, bash

Intermediate golang, sql

Previous Experience erlang, c, javascript, typescript, python, perl, php, glsl, clojure, rust, ocaml, lua

idioms

Spanish Native

English Upper Intermediate

job experience

Email Hosting Software Engineer III — Web.com

2017-2018

- Worked on the conversion of a Qmail based mail platform from Gentoo to Redhat.
- Created rpms/spec files.
- Worked on the development of a replacement for Qmail on the platform with a solution based on Dovecot.
- Implemented a logging solution based on Fluentd, Kafka and Postgres. To identify bad actors and blacklist them accordingly.
- Worked on optimizing current web performance, adding cache layers and investigating new load balance solutions.

Web Hosting Software Engineer II — Web.com

2014-2016

- Continuing to work on customer support escalation.
- Worked on wordpress multinetwork hosting platform, based on nginx and percona cluster (mysql).
- Packaging and maintaining all the software related to the Gentoo based shared hosting platform.
- Maintaing the in-house configuration management tools and related PXE servers and custom kernel build.
- Worked on the development of a nginx based proxy for SSL-termination. Developed in Lua scripts and redis.
- Deployed a Kubernetes cluster for development of internal applications.

Web Hosting Software Engineer I — Web.com

- Troubleshooting customer issues on a Unix shared web hosting platform.
- As the last level of support I was responsable of understanding in depth the issue and fiding the root cause of it.
- Which consisted of coding issues on the cx code, bad configuration on the server side or missing software configurations.

Jr. Linux System Administrator — Sols S.A.

2011

• Network design and deploy of a OpenVPN node and squid proxy. Maintenance and technical support.

education

Professional Penetration Tester	Base4 University	2015
Red Hat System Administrator I	IT Collage	2014
Systems Engineer	UTN - Incomplete	2010-2011

personal projects

React	 Golang + Typescript app to search through IRC logs, stored in postgres. Typescript app to generate an image and video gallery from a Reddit page.
Lisp	 Several game engines based on OpenGL Wrappers for multiple 3rd party C libraries Multiple audio, video and midi sequencers
Gentoo	 A Portage repository, to build 3rd party software. Minimal and target specific Docker images, using different libc's and Github Actions to build.
Bash	 Integrate several OSINT tools for automatic recon. Postgresql backed. HTML scrapper. Downloads wallpapers from 10 different sites.
Golang	 RSS feed generators, for twitch and github. Command line clients to view comments on imageboards, reddit, hackernews, twitter. IP address metadata gatherer, asking different cloud providers ans WHOIS.
Erlang	- Public DNS record monitor.
С	– System monitor using 'upower', 'x11', and 'postgres' libraries to record system state.
Latex	– This CV, written in LaTeX, build and published through Github Actions.